I'm on the Document.getElementsByClassName page.
أنا أتصفح الآن صفحة Document.getElementsByClassName.
And let's scroll down here just a bit.
لنمرر لأسفل قليلًا.
So, under these examples,
حسنًا، في هذه الأمثلة،
we can see a couple of examples with some code,
يمكننا رؤية العديد من الأمثلة التي تحتوي على بعض الأكواد،
and let's look at one of them.
دعونا نركِّز على مثال واحد منها.
We can see that it's a 'pre' tag with a number of different classes on it.
يمكننا رؤية وجود علامة 'pre' مع وجود عدد من الفئات المختلفة عليها.
But the one we're going to look at is line numbers.
لكن العدد الذي سنركِّز عليه هو عدد السطر.
So, here's a 'pre' tag with line numbers.
حسنًا، ها هي علامة 'pre' تحتوي على عدد سطر.
Here is a 'pre' tag with line numbers.
ها هي علامة 'pre' تحتوي على عدد سطر.
Here's one and here's another one.
ها هي واحد وها هي واحدة أخرى.
So, there are a number of items on this page with the class of line numbers.
حسنًا، يوجد عدد عناصر في هذه الصفحة مع فئة أعداد السطر.
Let's use the getElementsByClassName to take a look at them.
دعونا نستخدم getElementsByClassName لإلقاء نظرة عليها.
Invoking this function returns five items.
يرجع استدعاء هذه الدالة خمسة عناصر.
Looking at this character right here,
بالنظر إلى هذه الأحرف هنا،
this bracket, makes it look like it's an array that's returned.
ما بين هذه الأقواس، إنها تجعل الأمر يبدو على أنه مصفوفة تم إرجاعها.
But it's actually not.
لكن هذا الأمر في الحقيقة ليس كذلك.
If we open this up,
إذا فتحنا ذلك،
we can see that this is an HTML collection.
يمكن أن نرى أن هذا عبارة عن مجموعة HTML.
And looking at the documentation up here, we can see that,
وبالنظر إلى الوثائق الموجودة هنا، يمكن أن نرى أن
here's the documentation for how to write it out and it returns elements.
هذه هي الوثائق المتعلقة بكيفية كتابة ذلك وإرجاع العناصر.
Elements is a live HTML collection of
العناصر هي مجموعة HTML مباشرة
all of the elements that were found on the page with that class name.
من جميع العناصر التي تم العثور عليها في الصفحة باسم الفئة هذا.
So, getElementsByClassName doesn't return an array,
حسنًا إن getElementsByClassName لا يرجع أي مصفوفة،
it returns an HTML collection.
إنه يرجع مجموعة HTML.